

# **My Contact**

- sumitsahani174@gmail.com
- +91-9004844180
- Chembur Vashi Naka,Mumbai , India
- Iinkedin.com/in/sumit-sahani100b1121b/

# S/W Skills

- jQuery
- SQL server management studio
- Asp.net Asp.net MVC
- Asp.net core 3.1
- .Net core 5
- .Net core WebApi,
- Advanced Analytical Thinking Skills
- React Js

## **Soft Skills**

- Observation
- · Decision making
- Communication
- Multi-tasking

# Languages

- English
- Hindi
- Marathi

# **Education**

Chetana's Institute Of Management & Research

2015 - 2018 | BSc IT

#### **Interest**

- Music
- Gaming
- Chess

# SUMIT SAHANI SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

#### **Professional Profile**

A motivated 26 year old with great passion for technology and software development. Likes to work with Object Oriented Programming languages, with a preference to C#. Can work well in teams and finds clear communication important. Furthermore, likes to listen music and loves to play video games.

# **Experience**

#### **HDFC ERGO GIC | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER**

2022 - Present

#### **Key responsibilities:**

- Produce clean, efficient code based on specifications
- Integrate software components and third-party programs
- Verify and deploy programs and systems
- Testing and evaluating new programs
- Responsible for black / white box test and integration test.
- Developing quality assurance procedures
- Maintaining and upgrading existing systems
- Conducted / participated in code reviews as required

#### PROJECT - FIRE INSURANCE PRODUCT - BGR | 2022 - 2023

Technologies and Tools

- Visual Studio 2019
- Azure Git
- Visual Studio Code
- .net Core 6
- Oracle Database

#### THYROCARE TECHNOLOGY | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2019 - 2022

#### **Key responsibilities:**

- Team Lead, Software Programmer, Analysis of SRS
- Database Designing
- Implementing the Business Logic in C#

#### PROJECT - DSA Portal (Booking Web App) | 2021 - 2022

Technologies and Tools

- Net Core 3.1, Web API , Postman, MSSQL Server
- Entity Framework and Linq
- Visual Studio 2019
- Jquery Ajax

# **SUMIT SAHANI**

# SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

sumitsahani174@gmail.com || +91-9004844180

## **Achievements**

1st Price in Hardware Assembly by L.S.RAHEJA COLLEGE OF ARTS AND COMMERCE PARALLAX 2016-2017

#### **Activities**

Attended Workshop/ on VFX and ANIMATION conducted by Valia Centre of Excellence - July 2016

#### **About Me**

DOB : 27th April 1997 Nationality : Indian Gender : Male

# **Experience**

#### THYROCARE TECHNOLOGY | SOFTWARE DEVELOPER

2019 - 2022

#### PROJECT - RT-PCR Specific Test Booking Web App | 2019 - 21

Technologies and Tools

- Asp.net Framework 4.6,C#
- SQL Server ManagementStudio 2018
- Json Based Rest API Service,Bootstrap
- Jquery Ajax

#### **PROJECT - THYROCARE APIs | 2019**

Technologies and Tools

- .Net Core 3.1, Web API , Postman, MSSQL Server
- Entity Framework and Ling
- Visual Studio 2019, Jauery Ajax,
- Azure Portal for Hosting Identity Server 4 with JWT enabled authentication for the Security Purpose
- Developed on .Net Core 3.1 with Swagger UI to list down the developed APi's with Request and Response Structure